MAYANK GAIROLA

Address : LP-59A, MAURYA ENCLAVE, PITAMPURA, NEW DELHI-34

Phone No: +91-8447716546

E-mail: mayankgairola5@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

A strategic Project Management Professional offering more than 8 years of experience in managing Slope Mitigation, Ground Improvement and Strengthening Projects Planning; excels in managing end-to end activities including Project budgeting, scheduling, costing, coordination, resource utilization and procurement.

WORK EXPERIENCE: 8 YEARS AND 6 MONTHS

➤ CURRENT ORGANIZATION – Spar Geo Infra Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi

➤ DURATION – Jun-2019 till date

DESIGNATION
Deputy Manager- Planning

Responsibilities:

- Prepare and develop project plans & schedules according to standards and contractual terms & conditions
- Ensure that required resources and skill sets are available to meet the schedule
- Daily review of daily progress report with the site officials
- Analysis of Contract documents and resolving the related contractual issues (eg.-EoT, Variations etc.)
- Site coordination for issues related to progress of work
- Preparation of weekly/fortnightly/monthly project reports as per the requirement of management
- Preparation of monthly work planning and budgeting for sites
- Preparation of method statements for the projects
- Reviewing the planning and scheduling of work on current projects to ensure that activities are effectively planned, resourced and completed
- Supervising all construction activities including providing technical inputs for methodologies of construction
- Preparation of bills and work orders of contractors on ERP
- Follow up with procurement team to deliver the materials to site within schedule time
- Follow up with site team to process the monthly bills of contractors and vendors
- Raise purchase requisition for materials on ERP required as per project plans
- Materials and bills reconciliation
- Preparation of presentation for review meeting

Project Experience:

A. SLOPE MITIGATION PROJECTS

- 1. Restoration of National Highway NH-54 and mitigation of sinking area at Hunthar Veng, Aizawl, Mizoram
- Execution of Special Restoration/ Protective works for treatment of landslide & Slope failure between KM 0.00 to KM 2.40 (Region 1,3 & 5) on TCC-MAZA (Sector-III) Under 128RCC / 23BRTF under Project Arunank in Arunachal Pradesh

- 3. Execution of Rockfall protection/Stabilization works for treatment of fractured hard rock near Shere Thapa Bridge between KM 0.630 to KM 0.730 on Road TCC– Maza (Sector-I) under 128 RCC /23 BRTF under project Arunank in Arunachal Pradesh
- 4. Execution Of Slope Stabilisation Works And Erosion Control Works At Km 6.00 On Road TCC-MAZA (Four KMs From Galensiniak Bridge), KM 6.00 & KM 31.00 On Road Tama Chubg Chung-Taksing (Reddi Zigs) And KM 22.10 On Daporijo-Taliha Road Including Geological Investigation, Preparation Of Design And It's Proof Check From IIT Under 23 BRTF Under Project Arunank In Upper Subansiri District Of Arunachal Pradesh
- 5. Execution of Slope Stabilization and Rockfall Mitigation works at KM 314/220 to 314/300 including construction of R/wall along with steel dowels and thrie beam crash barrier at KM 314/200 to 314/300 on NH-5 Near Nigulsari, Tehsil Nichar of Distt. Kinnaur in Himachal Pradesh
- Execution of Slope Stabilization and Rockfall Mitigation works at KM 314/220 to 314/300 including construction of R/wall along with steel dowels and thrie beam crash barrier at KM 314/200 to 314/300 on NH-5 Near Nigulsari, Tehsil Nichar of Distt. Kinnaur in Himachal Pradesh
- 7. Sakaleshpura- Subrahmanya Road section-Strengthening & Protecting the side slopes of cutting by using chain link mesh netting with High strength galvanized steel wire rope at various locations between Sakleshpura and Subrahmanya road (Km 54/000-400, 57/000-600, 59/000-400, 67/000-100 & 83/000-300)
- 8. Rockfall Mitigation Works at Diversion Tunnel Inlet restoration above DT-2&3 and Diversion Tunnel outlet restoration above DT-4&5 for Subansiri Lower Hydro Electric Project, Gerukamukh, Assam
- 9. Land Slide risk mitigations at Raj Bhavan, Kharghuli, Guwahati-01, through Engineering, Procurement & Construction (EPC) mode

B. RIVER REVETMENT PROJECTS

- Flood Protection Work at Pandey Manjha jogia bund at Village Sheetal Manjha on L/B of Gurra river from KM 0.900 to 1.150 & from KM 3.000 to 3.200 using Concrete Mattress Technique
- 2. Flood Protection work on Pidra Karanpur Bund near Silahata Village between KM. 2.740 to 3.190 on Left bank of River Gurra in distt Deoria, UP
- Construction of Revetment and Pitching Work by Concrete GEO Mattress Technique Under Pilot Project between Km. 4.820 to 5.040 in 220.00 Mtr. Length of Katariya-Chandpur Embankment on Left Bank of River Ghaghara (Saryu) in Tehsil- Harriya, Distt-Basti, UP
- 4. Articulating Concrete Block Mattress work on Makhnaha Bund from KM: 1.450 to KM: 1.568 on right bank of River Rohin in District Gorakhpur, UP
- 5. Protection of South Bank of River Brahmaputra from Dikhowmukh to Rupahimukhusing articulated Grout Filled Mattress, Sivasagar, Assam
- Anti-Erosion work using Articulating Block Mattress and Silt retarder at Nakail Semrauna bund from KM 3.715 to 4.020 near Village Gaighat on Left bank of Rapti river in District Deoria, UP

ORGANIZATION – GRIPSINDIA (Joint Venture with Dywidag System)

International-DSI)

DURATION – Jul-2018 to May-2019

DESIGNATION - Site Engineer

Project Experience:

 Temporary Stay Cables for Chenab Arch Bridge over river Chenab on Katra -Laole section of Udhampur - Srinagar - Baramullah Rail link, J&K

Duration - July 2018 to May 2019 Contractor -

AFCONS Infrastructures Ltd.

Client - Konkan Railway Corporation Limited (KRCL)

ORGANIZATION – Freyssinet Menard India Pvt. Ltd.

DURATION – Jul-2015 to Jun-2018

DESIGNATION – Site Engineer

Project Experience:

 Fabrication and Installation of Rock Cable Anchors in slopes below S50 for Slope Stabilization in Chenab Railway Bridge Project across river Chenab, J&K

Duration - June 2017 to June 2018

Contractor - AFCONS Infrastructures Ltd.

Client - Konkan Railway Corporation Limited (KRCL)

 Protection / Treatment Work on Slopes of Trek between Ardhquari to Mata Vaishnodevi Bhawan (Phase -1), Katra, J&K

Duration - Mar 2017 to May 2017

Client - Shri Mata Vaishno Devi Shrine Board

Proposed Permanent Vertical Anchors for Express Exclusive Residential project, Royapettah, Chennai

Duration - Mar 2016 to Feb 2017

Client – Express Exclusive Developers Pvt. Ltd.

Post-Tensioning slabs in Office Building for ITC-Guntur Campus

Duration - July 2015 to Feb 2016

Contractor -L & T Construction Limited

Key Deliverables as a Site Engineer:

- Assist the team with day to day activities such as- Preparing progress reports, detailed projectdelivery programs, raise invoices, ensure overall project qualitycontrol & assurance.
- To assist in the development and implementation of work programs
- Store and inventory management
- Supervision of fabrication, installation and stressing work of anchors
- Monitoring of drilling and grouting activities
- Preparation of daily, weekly, monthly, reports on work progress
- Ensuring work with safety at site and preparation of safety reports
- Assist in Planning and Management of projects
- Assist with site inspection and prepare inspection and condition reports

- Supervision and monitoring of activities, ensuring that it is carried out to the appropriate technical standard and that is managed to program and budget
- Study and understanding of technical data and protocols provided by the designer
- To respond and work to personal deadlines for targets set to meet the requirements of programs of work, to meet client's need.
- Coordinate and cooperate with Clients and Contractors to resolve the site queries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Good knowledge of Post-tensioning works (i.e. Ground and rock anchoring, PT Slabs, PTBeam and Stay Cable Bridges)
- Proficient in Fabrication, Installation and Stressing work of Anchors
- Familiar with pressure grouting and consolidation grouting and worked with Grout Packers (i.e. Inflatable and Sleeve packer)
- Experience of working in Multi-Jack & Mono-Jack stressing systems
- Familiar with anchorages pre-assembly & installation, welding of HDPE pipes, cable lifting and installation and stressing works in cable stay bridges
- Knowledge of Slope mitigation and stabilization works- installation of Self drill anchor (SDA), wire mesh (Double twisted wiremesh, Rhomboidal cable net & Non-woven geotextile mat)and piling works
- Familiar with River Revetment works with installation of Unidirectional and Bidirectional Articulating Block (AB) Mattress

SOFTWARE SKILLS:

- Microsoft Office
- Microsoft Project 2013 (MSP)
- ERP
- AutoCAD

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION:

- ➤ **B.Tech** in **Mechanical Engineering** from Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam TechnicalUniversity, Uttar Pradesh, Year- 2011-2015
- Intermediate from Kendriya Vidyalaya No.1, Air Force Station, Agra (C.B.S.E Board) Year- 2010-2011
- ➤ **High School** from Kendriya Vidyalaya No.1, Air Force Station, Agra (C.B.S.E Board) Year- 2008-2009

STRENGTHS:

- Positive attitude
- Flexibility and Adaptability to work in any environment
- Quick learner
- Good at Teamwork
- Strong work ethics

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Date of birth : 13th Nov 1993 Languages known : English, Hindi

Marital Status : Single Nationality : Indian

HOBBIES & INTEREST:

Sports:- CricketListening to musicTraveling & Exploring

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that all the information given above is true and appropriate to the best of my knowledge.

Place: New Delhi MAYANK GAIROLA